Preliminary Guide to the Dabney Stuart-Fred Chappell Correspondence, 1984-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Dabney Stuart-Fred Chappell Correspondence 1984-2009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Chappell, Fred, 1936-
0.6 Linear Feet 150 Items
Fred Chappell is an author and a poet, and is a retired English professor from the University of North Carolina at Greensboro. Dabney Stuart is also an author and poet, and is a retired English professor at Washington and Lee University in Lexington, Virginia.
Accession (2009-0211) (150 items; 0.6 lin. ft.; dated 1984-2009) consists of Fred Chappell's letters to Dabney Stuart, covering a wide range of topics from personal stories and updates on families to his musings on literature and poetry in general. Chappell frequently offers feedback on Stuart's latest writings, as well as seeks input from Stuart on his own work. Occassional drafts are included for Stuart to read.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Dabney Stuart-Fred Chappell Correspondence were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2009.
Biographical Note
Fred Chappell is a poet and an author who has won numerous awards for his writings, including the Rockefeller Foundation Grant; the Nation Institute and American Academy award in literature; the Roanoke-Chowan Poetry Cup; the North Carolina Award in Literature; the Southeast Booksellers Association (SEBA) Book Award for fiction; and the Bollingen Prize in Poetry. He spent most of his career as an English professor at the University of North Carolina at Greensboro, and also served as Poet Laureate of North Carolina from 1997-2002.
Dabney Stuart is Chappell's close friend and is also an author and a poet. He is a retired English professor at Washington and Lee University in Lexington, Virginia. In addition to writing his own books and poems, Stuart served as editor of Shenandoah literary journal from 1988-1995.
Collection Overview
Accession (2009-0211) consists of Fred Chappell's letters to Dabney Stuart between 1984 and 2009. Most are handwritten by Chappell, and discuss both men's latest writings and activities, including family trips and academic conferences. Chappell frequently offers opinions on books that he has reviewed, as well as musings on literature in general. He often mentions Shenandoah, Stuart's literary journal from Washington and Lee University, and discusses his latest contributions. Chappell also provides feedback on Stuart's poetry, including works such as Light Years, Gospel Singer, Narcissus Dreaming, Don't Look Back, Long Gone, Sweet Lucy Wine, and Plain Talk.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Chappell, Fred, 1936-
Stuart, Dabney, 1937-
University of North Carolina at Greensboro
Authors -- North Carolina
Poets -- North Carolina
Greensboro (N.C.)
Correspondence
Related Material
Fred Chappell Papers
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence, 1984-2009, (1 box)
  - May 1984-July 1985 (Box 1)
  - September 1985-April 1986
  - April 1986-December 1986
  - July 1987-June 1988
  - June 1988-September 1989
  - October 1989-May 1990
  - June 1990-December 1990
  - January 1991-August 1991
  - September 1991-June 1993
  - July 1993-October 1993
  - November 1993-February 1994
  - January 1994-July 1994
  - July 1994-December 1995
  - January 1996-October 1999
  - July 2000-August 2009